Loren Sands-Ramshaw

Software engineer with 13 years of experience looking for a principal or staff position. Quick learner, great communicator, and clean coder. Good at writing, Googling, debugging, keyboard shortcuts, and getting things done.

lorensr@gmail.com (202) 680-4120 Brooklyn, NY

lorensr.me github.com/lorensr

EXPERIENCE

Author — The GraphQL Guide

2016 - 2021

Wrote and self-published an extensive book on GraphQL and its use with Node, React, React Native, Vue, Android, and iOS. graphql.guide

Consultant

2014 - 2020

Created, fixed, and added features to various web and mobile apps. Worked with many JavaScript environments and libraries, including React, Node, React Native, Cordova, Firebase, Amplify, AppSync, Cypress, Next.js, and Meteor.

CTO — Parlay Technology, Inc.

2014 - 2016

Built a cross-platform mobile app for challenging your friends and making predictions. Notable features included real-time updates, P2P payments (USD and BTC), and CSS animations. parlaywith.me

Global Network Vulnerability Analyst — NSA

2010 - 2012

Developed apps with Rails, Backbone, CoffeeScript, and Android. Computer Network Operations Development Program. TS//SCI clearance. Wrote a #1 Hacker News essay on my experience.

EDUCATION

National Cryptologic School

2010 - 2012

Studied network security, web application security, computer network operations, malware analysis, assembly language, network programming, C programming, Linux and Windows kernels, and cryptography.

Dartmouth College — B.A. in Computer Science

2006 - 2010

Magna cum laude. Honors thesis. Java, C, Scheme, Haskell, Algorithms, Software Design, Computational Neuroscience, Networking, Security, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture, Theory of Computation.

SKILLS

Full-stack JavaScript web and mobile app development

GraphQL, React, Node, Testing, Security, UX

Communication

LEADERSHIP

Managed devs in some consulting gigs and interns at Parlay. Mentored devs outside of work.

Took many emotional intelligence workshops and training programs.

Led various organizations, including a residential community (2016-present), fraternity, a capella group, and chess team.

TA'ed and taught sections for 9 CS courses at Dartmouth.

OPEN SOURCE

GraphQLGuide/guide Extensive example application used in my book

login-links Full-stack Meteor package for login links (OTPs)

meteor-synapsepay Full-stack Meteor package for ACH and KYC

HOBBIES

Authentic relating, swing dancing, investing, psychology, sci-fi/fantasy